<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on Marko Toplak</title>
    <link>https://toplak.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on Marko Toplak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toplak.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/bridge/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago I could not do a bridge. It did not seem hard, but when I tried, I could not do it. I managed to lift myself up for a few centimeters for an instant, but that was it.
That was years ago. Now I do it better. Video from January 2019:
[Bridge, January 2019, video](/bridge/201901.s.mp4)  I should have more weight over my hands. I will fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our tango performances</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/performance/</guid>
      <description>This is how we dance.
December 2018 - Milonga Linda We were invited to perform at Milonga Linda in Ljubljana. This was our first performance in front of a tango-educated audience. The performance motivated us to practice more.
We were very nervous. We improvised everything&amp;mdash;nothing was set. I like the third song we danced the most:
 Anibal Troilo - El motivo  Our best dance was actually the additional song, where we dance with the performances from previous editions of Milonga Linda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango DJ</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/dj/</guid>
      <description>I started dancing tango because I liked the music. Now I occasionally play music at milongas. On this page:
 Being a tango DJ The great four Sound quality Previous milongas  
Being a tango DJ In tango we always dance to, if I exaggerate a bit, to the same 25 songs. Still, each milonga feels special. If the selection of music&amp;mdash;order of songs and their combinations&amp;mdash;is good, everything flows better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Computer geek I started programming in the last years of primary school. Programming was something only the coolest people did. For some years I tried to learn Pascal, but I only managed to copy examples from the book. I also built web pages, but that was not real programming. I only started think like a programmer when I was forced to do it. I wanted to host an IRC bot on a VAX/VMS server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/now/</guid>
      <description>I mainly:
 Program. Workout. Dance tango. Sleep.  During the week I walk to the Soleil Synchrotron, France, where I am a post-doc. I am trying to extend Orange, a visual programming toolkit for data analysis, so that it will handle spectral data and perhaps also data from tomography. We call our project Quasar.
If tango does not make me too tired, I follow the GMB Integral Strength workout program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>