<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marko Toplak</title>
    <link>https://toplak.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marko Toplak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toplak.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero point, useless? (tango)</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/tango-zero-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/tango-zero-point/</guid>
      <description>Diego Ortega and Aldana Silveira. They are one of the few couples that I find magical. When I start watching them, I easily get lost in their videos. I do not have a complete answer on why I like them so much, but I am sure I am fascinated by how they connect steps. It is hard to see where their step finishes and the next one starts: they link them so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango DJ</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/dj/</guid>
      <description>I started dancing tango because I liked the music. Now I occasionally play it at milongas. On this page:
 Being a tango DJ The great four Sound quality Previous milongas  
Being a tango DJ In tango we always dance to, if I exaggerate a bit, to the same 25 songs. Still, each milonga feels special. If the selection of music&amp;mdash;order of songs and their combinations&amp;mdash;is good, everything flows better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango classes</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/classes/</guid>
      <description>I teach regular classes with Vlasta Veselko. Our classes are in Slovenian, so please check my Slovenian description or Vlasta&amp;rsquo;s page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connection in tango</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/connection/</guid>
      <description>Some years ago two girls came to the Carmencita milonga in Ljubljana. I saw them for the first time. I thought they were beginners. For the first hour they were just sitting in a corner and observing the milonga. Then I invited one of them to dance.
When we started dancing, something felt odd. She was a tiny girl, but, when we were dancing, she seemed so big! I knew exactly what she was doing with her body: through our embrace I felt her feet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontainebleau for beginner climbers</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/bleau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/bleau/</guid>
      <description>Some say that you should not go to Fontainebleau if you are not a high level climber. I strongly disagree: also for beginners, it is one of the best climbing spots. I have not found such diverse problems at a single spot anywhere else.
The Fontainebleau forest is covered with sandstone boulders, where generations of Parisians practised for long climbs in the Alps. Afterwards, bouldering developed as an independent activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/bridge/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago I could not do a bridge. It did not seem hard, but when I tried, I could not do it. I managed to lift myself up for a few centimeters for an instant, but that was it.
That was years ago. Now I do it better. Video from January 2019:
[Bridge, January 2019, video](/bridge/201901.s.mp4)  I should have more weight over my hands. I will fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our tango performances</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/performance/</guid>
      <description>This is how we dance.
December 2018 - Milonga Linda We were invited to perform at Milonga Linda in Ljubljana. This was our first performance in front of a tango-educated audience. The performance motivated us to practice more.
We were very nervous. We improvised everything&amp;mdash;nothing was set. I like the third song we danced the most:
 Anibal Troilo - El motivo  Our best dance was actually the additional song, where we dance with the performances from previous editions of Milonga Linda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Computer geek I started programming in the last years of primary school. Programming was something only the coolest people did. For some years I tried to learn Pascal, but I only managed to copy examples from the book. I also built web pages, but that was not real programming. I only started think like a programmer when I was forced to do it. I wanted to host an IRC bot on a VAX/VMS server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/now/</guid>
      <description>I mainly:
 Take care of my 3-year-old son. Teach data analysis. Write computer programs. Dance argentine tango.  I am trying to extend Orange, a visual programming toolkit for data analysis, so that it will handle spectral data and perhaps also data from tomography. We call our project Quasar.
This semester I am an assistant for two courses at the Faculty of Computer and Information Science in Ljubljana: (1) Introduction to data mining and (2) Machine learning for data science 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>