<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marko Toplak</title>
    <link>https://toplak.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marko Toplak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toplak.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango DJ</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/dj/</guid>
      <description>I started dancing tango because I liked the music. Now I occasionally play it at milongas. On this page:
 Being a tango DJ The great four Sound quality Previous milongas  
Being a tango DJ In tango we always dance to, if I exaggerate a bit, to the same 25 songs. Still, each milonga feels special. If the selection of music&amp;mdash;order of songs and their combinations&amp;mdash;is good, everything flows better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontainebleau for beginner climbers</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/bleau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/bleau/</guid>
      <description>Some say that you should not go to Fontainebleau if you are not a high level climber. I strongly disagree: also for beginners, it is one of the best climbing spots. I have not found such diverse problems at a single spot anywhere else.
The Fontainebleau forest is covered with sandstone boulders, where generations of Parisians practised for long climbs in the Alps. Afterwards, bouldering developed as an independent activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/bridge/</guid>
      <description>Three years ago I could not do a bridge. It did not seem hard, but when I tried, I could not do it. I managed to lift myself up for a few centimeters for an instant, but that was it.
That was years ago. Now I do it better. Video from January 2019:
[Bridge, January 2019, video](/bridge/201901.s.mp4)  I should have more weight over my hands. I will fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our tango performances</title>
      <link>https://toplak.io/performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toplak.io/performance/</guid>
      <description>This is how we dance.
December 2018 - Milonga Linda We were invited to perform at Milonga Linda in Ljubljana. This was our first performance in front of a tango-educated audience. The performance motivated us to practice more.
We were very nervous. We improvised everything&amp;mdash;nothing was set. I like the third song we danced the most:
 Anibal Troilo - El motivo  Our best dance was actually the additional song, where we dance with the performances from previous editions of Milonga Linda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>